Brandon Whisnant

■ bc.whisnant@gmail.com in/brandon-c-whisnant

SUMMARY

Software engineer with a decade of professional experience. I mainly work on the frontend but have experience in many other things and handle multiple responsibilities/specialities well. I like to build things and I'm passionate about making products that are actually usable. I mainly work on tasks that are both high priority and high impact. My main goal is to leave any product I work on better than I found it.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Liveschool, Inc.

July 2021 - Present, Remote · Remote

- · Javascript | Typescript | Vue.js | Vuex | Firebase | iOS
- Frontend development with a focus on vue.js. Working on a hybrid application involving a legacy js codebase that has vue integrated. Also working on other vue projects. Responsible for deploying to aws for gamma and prod environments. I also handle most things related to iOS development/app store deployment. This includes resolving issues in the codebase that cause unique issues on the iOS platform and fixing things that prevent us from shipping to testflight/the app store itself.

Frontend Developer

vandePoel Productions

October 2019 - February 2021, Remote

- · Javascript | Vue.js | Nuxt.js | Typescript
- · Working on a small team of developers that creates event management websites using vue and nuxt js along with third party libraries like vuetify, cypress and veevalidate. Covering the whole process for registrations including applying, creating and editing. Taking on more responsibilities including mentoring as time allows.
- I created a template we could use to create our sites faster by mainly switching out assets and adding any custom function needed. This resulted in the turnaround time cut in half for our smaller events.
- $\cdot \text{ Also used cypress to make sure the code that I was writing had end to end tests to ensure everything worked as expected.}\\$

Software Developer

Pivotal Energy Solutions

December 2018 - October 2019, Remote

- · Javascript | Vue.js
- Developing web based energy efficiency reporting software using vue js components. I am creating the front end from the ground up using custom components and dynamic data retrieved from the backend.

Frontend Developer

Locus Technologies

August 2018 - December 2018, Asheville, North Carolina Area

- · Javascript | React
- Worked on a legacy environmental, health and safety web application. Also used React for refactoring older pages since we were moving to a single page application architecture.

UI Developer

CRG

May 2018 - August 2018, May 2018 - Aug 2018 · 4 mos

 \cdot UI Development with Angular 1.

Software / Application Developer

Global Payments Inc.

November 2017 - April 2018, Charlotte, North Carolina Area

· Worked on a custom point of sale system using Angular 2+. My duty as a contractor was creating new components, styling them and updating older components that need revised.

Frontend Developer

MicroD

- · Designed, implemented and optimized the process of taking new sites live and updating existing sites to new, responsive themes.
- Expanded knowledge of new and current employees by training and mentoring them about the basics of code and how that related to their duties.
- · Increased customer satisfaction by delivering earlier on projects than expected and insuring that standards were exceeded.
- Worked on high priority websites such as www.smithe.com and www.hookerfurniture.com to make improvements and changes using javascript for functionality and user interaction.

Associate Support Technician

Lowe's Companies, Inc.

2013 - October 2015, Wilkesboro, NC

- · Assisted the store employees of Lowe's with any problem related to proprietary tools or Windows operating system.
- · Investigated and solved issues with the Unix based point of sales system that was used in store.

CNC Specialist

Thomasville Home Furnishings

2008 - 2013, Lenoir, NC

• Programmed numerous CNC machines including a small four head Heian, large eight head Heian, and large four head Shoda. Also programmed a 3 axis CR Onsrud machine that had 5 axis emulation features. Used Mastercam to program the machines, Autocad and AutoDesk inventor to design and inspect parts. Also made templates for all of the knives that were made within the plant. Fixed all pc issues within the plant including replacing physical components and troubleshooting operating system problems.

EDUCATION

Backend Development

Boot.dev · November 2024

Frontend Nanodegree, Software Development

Udacity · 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Boot.dev's Learn Object Oriented Programming Course

Boot.dev · 2024

Boot.dev's Learn Python Course

Boot.dev · 2024

Boot.dev's Learn JavaScript Course

Boot.dev · 2023

SKILLS

Industry Knowledge: TypeScript, Go (Programming Language), Front-end Development, Software Development

Tools & Technologies: Python (Programming Language), Vue.js, Javascript, React.js, Nuxt.js, Node.js, Python, iOS